俗话说得没错
It is true what they say:
怀胎三月肚如鼓
Pregnant bellies look like a drum.
我肚子大得已经挎不上吉他了
I'm so pregnant that my guitar doesn't fit anymore.
所以我打算在生产前
So I thought till I'm not,
就用这个鼓来伴奏
I'm just gonna play all my songs on this drum.
听起来超酷的
It sounds really cool!
你们听
Listen, listen.
臭臭猫  臭臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat
他们喂你吃什么
What are they feeding you
菲比  太棒了
Pheobe, that sounds great!
是很棒吧  而且我才练了1小时
I know! I know! And I've only been playing for like an hour.
菲比  菲比  你好
Pheobe, Pheobe, hi.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
我得麻烦你帮我个大忙
Actually, I came down to ask you a big favor.
别告诉我你还想往我子宫里塞东西
Don't tell me you want to keep more of your stuff in my uterus.
不  不会的
No, no, no.
是这样的
Okay. Now, see.
我想给女孩取名莱丝莉
I want to name the girl baby Leslie.
弗兰克想给其中一个男孩取名
And Frank wants to name one of the boy babies
弗兰克二世二世
Frank Jr., Jr..
不应该是弗兰克三世吗
Wouldn't that be Frank III?
一提这个我就来气
Don't get me started.
既然有三个宝宝
Anyway, since there are three babies
我们又一人取了一个名字
and we both got to put our names in
如果你能给另一个男孩起名的话
we would be truly honored
我们会倍感荣幸
if you would name the other boy baby.
那太好了
That's so nice!
美洲狮
Cougar.
你先慢慢想
Think about it.
我有件胸罩晾在浴帘杆上了
I left a bra drying on the shower rod.
你不会觉得你儿子会认为是你的
You don't think your son would think it's yours
而心灵受创吧
and be horribly traumatized?
当妈的都能有老婆  当爹的就可以戴文胸
Mommy can have a wife. Daddy can have a bra.
该走了
It's time to go.
不  那个钟有点快
Oh, no no no. See, that clock's a little fast.
我们还有17分钟
We still have 17 minutes.
17分钟内我们都能做什么呢
What can we do in 17 minutes...
还能做两次
...twice?
你真有野心
Well, that's ambitious.
别理它
You can ignore that.
是卡罗尔带你儿子来了
That's Carol with your son.
相信我  等他长大一定会谅解的
Believe me, when he's older, he'll understand.
-罗斯  -马上就来
- Ross  - I'll be right there.
你好  你好啊
Hello! Hello!
艾蜜莉  这是卡罗尔和苏珊
Emily, This is Carol and Susan.
-见到你真高兴  -我也是
- It's so nice to finally meet you. - You too.
苏珊下周要去伦敦拍广告
Susan will be shooting a commercial in London next week.
我好兴奋  我还没去过伦敦呢
I'm so excited. I've never been there.
-我来给你介绍  -那太好了
- I'll show you around. - That'd be great!
我还想看表演
Also, I was hoping to catch a show.
你有什么建议吗
So if you can make any suggestions?
好玩的地方多着呢
There's tons of terrific stuff.
我陪你去吧
I'll go with you.
你们可真聊得来
Look at you two bonding.
去机场都快来不及了
Making us late for the airport.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
他没事的
It's fine, it's fine.
他不喜欢我们处得来
It's just us getting along is difficult for him,
因为他不喜欢我
because he doesn't like me.
得了吧  其实...
Come on. That's...
没错
It's true.
名字想好了吗
Do we have a baby name yet?
还没  太难了
No. It's so hard!
翻完这本书也没找着个好的
I went through this book and found nothing.
我想取个威猛而自信的名字
I want a name that's really like, you know, strong and confident.
比如  埃克森
You know? Like... Exxon!
它旗下的瓦尔迪兹号可真威猛
It certainly worked for that Valdez kid.
你要起个威猛的名字吗
You want a strong name?
"一只绿巨人"如何
How about The Hulk?
绿巨人我不敢说
I'm not sure about Hulk,
不过我喜欢以"一只"开头的
but I like a name starting with "The".
想取好名就取乔伊
You want a good name, go with Joey.
乔伊是你的好朋友  乔伊是你的好兄弟
Joey's your pal, Joey's your buddy.
人都在哪里  都在跟乔伊在一起
Where is everybody? They're hanging out with Joey!
嘿  如果要这样
Hey, if you are going to do that.
取乔伊还不如叫钱德勒
If you're going to name him Joey, you should name him Chandler.
钱德勒既风趣又深刻还很可爱
Chandler's funny, sophisticated, and very lovable
如果你了解他
once you get to know him.
乔伊也很可爱
Joey's lovable too.
重要的是  当你需要乔伊  他就会出现
But the thing with Joey is, if you need him, he'll be there.
钱德勒也会出现
Chandler will be there for you too.
他可能有点慢
I mean, he might be a little late
不过他一定会出现  他还会带冰汽水来
but he'll be there. And he'll bring you cold soda
如果你找他是因为你热得发烫
if what you need him for is that you're really hot.
你怎么想
What do you say?
跟我爱的人同名的想法很好
I like the idea of naming him after someone I love.
乔伊和钱德勒都是很棒的名字
Joey and Chandler are both great names.
但是我不...
All right, I don't...
不如就叫"一只绿巨人"好了
Maybe I'll just name him The Hulk.
真不该提
I shouldn't have mentioned it.
那是我留给我孩子的
That's what I wanted to name my kid that.
如果第一次跟约书亚上床的话
If you were hoping to sleep with Joshua for the first time,
你会穿哪一件
which one would you wanna be wearing?
帮别人挑性感内衣的事我做不来
It really creeps me out choosing other people's sex clothes.
对不起  我太兴奋了
I'm sorry. I'm just so excited.
这事我等了好几个月了  跑去染了发
I've been waiting for this for months. I got my hair colored.
换了新床单  还要给他做大餐
I got new sheets. I'm making him a very fancy meal.
我要给他做什么菜来着
What am I making him, by the way?
你打算给他做
Well, you are making him
松子山羊奶酪菊苣沙拉
a frisee salad with goat cheese and pine nuts
菰米饭  烤芦笋和酥皮鲑鱼
wild rice, roasted asparagus and salmon en croute.
我以为是要做菲力牛排
I thought I was making him filet mignon.
对  可后来你决定做鲑鱼
Yes, you were, but then you decided to make salmon
因为餐厅的鲑鱼有剩
because you had some left over at the restaurant.
然后你要知道要是你抱怨
Then you realized if you bitched about it,
你姐就会罢煮
then you would stop cooking
你就得上可乐烤土豆
and you would have to make your famous baked potato and Diet Coke.
我姐煮菜时火气真大
I really get crabby when I cook.
艾蜜莉昨晚打电话来
So Emily called last night.
你现在才转告我
And now you're giving me the message?
艾蜜莉爱死苏珊了
Turns out that Emily is just crazy about Susan.
她们一起去看戏
They're going to the theater together.
她们一起吃晚饭
They're going to dinner.
她们还一起去骑马
They're going horseback riding!
苏珊真会玩
God, Susan is so fun!
这个情节太熟悉了一点
Look, this is just a little too familiar.
我和卡罗尔分手前半年
For six months before Carol and I split up,
我听到的只有"我朋友苏珊好聪明"
all I heard was, "My friend Susan is so smart.
"我朋友苏珊好风趣"
My friend Susan is so funny.
"我朋友苏珊好棒"
My friend Susan is so great."
你担心艾蜜莉和苏珊会擦出火花吗
You actually think something could happen between Emily and Susan?
她们都一起去健身房了
Hey, they're going to the gym together!
两个女人...
Two women...
劈腿拉筋
...stretching!
健身完洗个桑拿  然后就该互相调戏了
They take a steam, things get playful.
你们没看过《登峰造极》吗
Did't you see Personal Best?
没  但我一定要看
No, but I'm gonna!
先生  您疯了
Hi! You're crazy.
那可是艾蜜莉  艾蜜莉是直女
This is Emily. Emily is straight.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我和卡罗尔结婚前也以为她是直女
We thought Carol was straight before I married her.
我肯定不喜欢罗斯这个名字
Yeah, definitely. I don't like the name Ross.
你落井下石的方式还真怪
What a weird way to kick me when I'm down!
不  我是说宝宝的名字
No, no, I meant for the baby.
罗斯这名字有什么不好
What's wrong with Ross?
绿巨人就不会遇上这种事
Something like this would never happen to The Hulk, you know.
其实  也并非如此
Actually, that's not true.
《无敌绿巨人》72话  布鲁斯·班纳博士发现...
In The Incredible Hulk, number 72, Dr. Bruce Banner found...
那个...
You know...
算了  我女朋友都成拉拉了
Never mind. My girlfriend's a lesbian.
我决定从乔伊和钱德勒里二选一
So, I decided I'm definitely going to go with either Joey or Chandler.
你一定要选乔伊
You gotta pick Joey!
有哪个名人叫钱德勒
Name one famous person named Chandler.
雷蒙·钱德勒
Raymond Chandler.
你捏造的人不算
Someone you didn't make up.
叫乔伊的才没有名人呢  除了
There are no famous Joeys. Except for...
乔伊·巴塔弗柯
...Joey Buttafuoco.
他的确是我们的心头之痛
Yeah, that guy really hurt us.
折中一下如何  比如...
How about a compromise then? What if it's...
钱诺伊
...Chan-no-ey?
乔伊  你好好想想
Joey? Think about it.
首先  他绝对当不上总统
First of all, he'll never be president.
绝对不会出现乔伊总统
There will never be a President Joey.
听着  我本来不想提的
Alright, look man. I didn't want to bring this up.
但钱德勒是我听过最蠢的名字
But Chandler is the stupidest name I've heard in my life!
它根本不是名字  连个词都不是
It's not a name! It's barely even a word.
念着像"前吊灯"但又不是
It's like chandelier but it's not!
它是个蠢到爆的非名字
It's a stupid, stupid, non-name!
你说得对  我的名字烂透了
You're right. I have a horrible, horrible name.
对不起  我不是...对不起
I'm sorry, man. I didn't, I'm sorry.
没事
It's okay.
所以就是乔伊喽
So I guess it's Joey then. I mean.
好丰盛  谢谢你这么费心
This is so nice. Thank you for doing this.
别客气  烹饪能给我以安慰
Please! Cooking soothes me.
我们开吃吧
So dig in!
看起来都好好吃
It all looks so good.
老天
Oh, my God.
我知道  天呐  这个米饭好...
I know. My God, this rice is so...
我的手艺真好
I am so good!
你后面
Behind you.
没事  它们以前住这里  有时会迁徒回来
They used to live here, and sometimes they migrate back over.
能不能让它们不要在这里
Is there some way that they could not be here?
我最怕家禽了
Farm birds really kind of freak me out!
-好  -出去
- Okay, okay. - Here we go.
出去
There you go!
你们怎么学会敲门的  进来
Hey! How'd you do that?  Come in.
都走了
All gone.
怕家禽是吧
So, farm birds, huh?
这是我唯一的怪毛病  我发誓
It's my only weird thing, I swear.
我想告诉你的  但我没想到它们会在这里
I would have told you. But I didn't know that they'd be here.
要不要来点...
Can I serve you a little...
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
只是我还能感觉到它们的存在
It's just that I know that they're still out there.
它们在对门  隔着两道墙
They're across the hall. That's two doors away.
它们得啄很久才能把墙啄穿
It'll take them a long time to peck their way back over here.
我笑不出来
That's not funny.
那换个地方会不会好点
Would you feel better if we went someplace else?
我们可以把东西打包去你家
We could pack this stuff up and go to your apartment.
这周我家在装修  一团混乱
They're working on it this week. It's a total mess.
我暂住我父母家  咱们可以去那里
I'm staying at my parents' house. We could go there.
-你父母  -他们出游了
- Your parents? - They're out of town.
那里地方很大  后院很美
It's a huge place, and it's got this gorgeous view in the park.
会很浪漫的
It'd be very romantic.
-如何  -好啊
- What do you say? - Yeah, that works.
它们闻得出恐惧
They can smell the fear.
本好吗
How's Ben?
我问他要不要吃东西  他说不要
I asked if he wanted to eat. He said no.
我问他要不要睡觉  他说不要
I asked if he wanted to sleep. He said no.
我问他想做什么  他说不要
I asked what he wanted to do. He said no.
所以他在扫地
So he's sweeping.
有苏珊的消息吗
Any word from Susan?
她说她跟艾蜜莉玩得很开心
She said she's having so much fun with Emily.
对了  你有没有想过
By the by, did it ever occur to you that
她们或许太开心了一点
maybe they might be having a little too much fun?
什么叫太开心
What's too much fun?
我们是夫妻时你和苏珊的那种开心
The kind of fun you and Susan had when we were married.
天呐  你真会乱想
Oh, my God! You are so paranoid.
-是吗  -是
- Am I? - Yes.
是吗
Am I?
我不知道艾蜜莉
I can't speak for Emily.
但苏珊和我的关系很稳定
But Susan is in a loving, committed relationship.
卡罗尔  我们曾经也是
Carol, so were we.
你就想像一下
Just imagine for a moment
苏珊认识了别人然后她们一拍即合
that Susan meets someone, and they hit it off.
她们从剧院回来
They're coming back from the theater,
去酒吧喝个小酒
and they stop at a pub for a couple of drinks.
有说有笑
They're laughing.
其中一个不小心碰了下另一个
Someone innocently touches someone else.
一碰就擦出了火花
There's electricity.
感觉很新鲜  很刺激
It's new. It's exciting.
你敢说完全没有可能
Are you saying there isn't the slightest possibility
出点什么事
of something happening?
-或许吧  -天呐
- Maybe. - Oh, my God!
听你一说我彻底绝望了
I didn't really believe it until you just said it!
别的小朋友都不信
Even though none of the other kids believed me,
但那只鸭子真的推了我
I swear to God that duck pushed me.
这里真豪华
This place is fabulous!
我带你走走
Let me show you around.
这是楼下的客厅
This is the downstairs living room.
居然有两个客厅
There's two living rooms?
你从小在这长大
Growing up here,
肯定帮你引来不少妹子吧
this place must have been a real babe magnet.
本来是的  但我父母刚搬来
It would have been, but my parents just moved here.
这地方能帮你引来很多妹子的
You should know this place is a real babe magnet.
要亲热吗
Want to make out?
这样吧  我去把吃的放冰箱
Hey, here's an idea. Why don't I put the food in the fridge
我们待会再吃
and we can eat it later?
听起来不错
That sounds like a plan.
哪里可以让我梳洗一下
Is there a place that I could go freshen up?
有  直走左边第二个门
Just down the hall and second door to your left.
-儿子  -你们怎么回来了
- Hi, darling. - What are you guys doing here?
-我们提前结束了  -法国烂透了
- We cut the trip short. - France sucks!
情况有点特殊  我正约会呢
This may be a little weird, but I've got a date here.
了解
Say no more.
我们拿了吃的就上楼  不妨碍你
We'll grab some food, take it with us upstairs and be out of your hair.
那好  你们都没去意大利
That'd be great. So you didn't even get to Italy?
没有  糟透了
Yep. Sucks!
你来了
Hi, you!
我的神
Oh, my God!
我知道  我不光会做菜
I know. I can do more than cook.
我喜欢她  她挺聪明的
I like her. She seems smart.
瑞秋  我爸妈
Rachel, my parents.
很高兴认识你们
So nice to meet you.
约书亚  那500块是给你买日用品的
Joshua, that $500 was for groceries.
什么  这...不  你们误会了
What, this? Oh, no. That's not what it is.
我在时装界工作
Okay, I work in fashion.
这其实是正式的着装
And this is a real dress, actually.
在米兰满街都是穿这个的
They're wearing it in Milan.
我工作的一部分就是试穿不同衣服
Part of my job is to wear the clothes
观察大众的反应
and see how people respond.
然后回报给布明岱尔百货的上司
Then I report back to my superiors at Bloomingdale's.
很显然  这个情况
Obviously, in this case
我得汇报说
I am going to report back:
美国  暂不适合
"U.S.A. Not ready."
洛杉矶或许可以
Maybe in L.A.
-对  -有道理
- Yes  - There you go!
你们吃过饭了吗
Have you kids eaten yet?
我们想完事儿再吃...我是说  正要吃
We were going to do that after. I mean, next.
我们饿死了
We were starving .
大家一起出去吃吧
Why don't we all get something to eat?
也好  穿着它窝在家里太可惜了
No use wasting this baby just lying around the house.
所以我们去吃饭
So we'll go eat.
你就穿那样
You'll wear that.
我们吃着饭  你还是穿成那样
We'll be eating and, of course, you'll be wearing that.
我为我说的话道歉
I am sorry about what I said.
不  你说得对  这个名字太可笑了
Nope, you're right. It is a ridiculous name!
也没那么糟
It's not bad.
当然有
Yes, it is!
从此以后  我不要名了
From now on, I have no first name.
你就叫宾
You're just Bing?
我无名无姓
I have no name.
那我们要叫你什么
So what are we supposed to call you?
好  现在的话你们就叫我...
Okay, for now, temporarily, you can call me...
克林
Clint.
想叫这名你还不够酷
No way are you cool enough to pull off "Clint."
那我可以叫什么
What name am I cool enough to pull off?
吉恩
Gene.
就是克林
It's Clint.
It's Clint!
-回见  吉恩  -再见  吉恩
- See you later, Gene. - Bye, Gene.
是克林  克林
It's Clint! Clint!
吉恩怎么了
What's up with Gene?
你穿睡衣出去吃饭了
You wore your nightie to dinner?
没错
Oh, yeah.
最精彩的是服务员把水泼到了我背上
And the best part was when the waiter spilled water down my back.
我一跳  奶子弹了出来
I jumped up and my boob popped out.
天呐
Oh, no!
没关系  我的胸型很漂亮
It's all right. I got nice boobs.
我刚收到艾蜜莉的留言
I just picked up a message from Emily.
她和苏珊要一起去读诗会
She and Susan are going to a poetry reading together.
-所以呢  -所以呢
- So? - So?
读诗会
Poetry?
苏珊是同志
Susan's gay.
她们要"天下大同"了
They're being gay together!
艾蜜莉是直女
Emily's straight.
你醒醒吧
Oh, wake up!
卡罗尔真的把你害惨了
Wow! Carol really messed you up.
你说什么
Excuse me?
她害你变成了个多疑  猜忌  爱吃飞醋的
She turned you into this untrusting, crazy, jealous...
马屁精
sycophant!
我不知道"马屁精"是什么意思
So I don't know what "sycophant" means,
不过剩下的都说对了
but the rest is right.
你们都在胡说什么
What are you talking about?
我才没有吃醋上瘾呢
I am not a crazy, jealous person.
怎么了
What?
她说得没错
She's totally right.
我们在一起时  你老吃马克的醋
When we were together, you got all freak out about Mark,
其实我俩什么都没有
and there was nothing.
太有道理了
This totally makes sense.
根本乱讲
It does not!
太说得通了
Sure it does.
高中时你从不吃醋
In high school, you were not jealous at all...
尽管你每个女友都劈腿
even though all your girlfriends cheated on you.
一直到92  93年他都很信任别人
So up until '92, '93, he was very trusting.
然后94年来袭  卡罗尔离开他
Then '94 hit, Carol left him,
一下就变得捕风捉影
and bam! Paranoid City!
就是这样  一点没错
Absolutely! Absolutely!
太好玩了
This is so much fun!
一点也不好玩
This is not fun!
听着  我们只想说
Look, all we're trying to say is
别让你和卡罗尔的悲剧
don't let what happened with Carol
影响你和艾蜜莉的感情
ruin what you've got with Emily.
92年的罗斯就不会
The '92 Ross wouldn't.
我还是觉得马克一定不老实
I still think I was right about that Mark thing.
什么  你知道吗
Wh-What, you know what?
我希望艾蜜莉就是拉拉
I hope Emily is a lesbian.
划鼓
Drumroll.
好了
Okay, okay, all right.
帮个忙
Help!
我适合马克还是约翰
Am I a Mark or a John?
你当马克不够高
You're not tall enough to be a Mark.
不过你或许能当个好巴尼
But you might make a good Barney.
我是认真的
Look, I am serious.
明天3点半我就要上法院
Tomorrow at 3:30, I'm going down to the courthouse.
你真的要改名
You're actually going through with this?
这个名字拖累了我一辈子
This name has been holding me back my entire life.
害我被其他同学找茬
It's probably why kids picked on me in school
害我没有桃花运
and why I never do well with women.
明天4点起
So at 4 o'clock tomorrow,
我不是马克·约翰森就是约翰·马克森
I'm either gonna be Mark Johnson or John Markson.
你的问题在于你  与名字无关
You've got problems because of you, not your name!
别再闹了  钱德勒这个名字很棒
This has got to stop! Chandler is a great name.
事实上...好
In fact...yes.
对不起  我知道你希望宝宝叫乔伊
I'm sorry, I know you wanted me to name the baby Joey.
但我要...我要给孩子取名钱德勒
I'm going to name the baby Chandler.
真的吗
Really?
对  但你也得保留这个名字
But you have to keep the name too.
好  谢了
Okay, thanks!
要不要抱一下
You want to hug it out?
我现在就去告诉弗兰克和爱丽丝
I'm going to go tell Frank and Alice right now!
菲比  再见
Bye, Pheebs!
再见
Okay, bye!
-很棒的行李箱  -我正要说
- Nice luggage. - I was going to say.
-我好想你  -我也是
- I miss you. - I missed you too.
-谢谢你  我玩得很开心  -我也是
- Thanks, I had a great time. - So did I.
不是舌吻
No tongue.